KENNETH RAMSEY

Austin, TX 512-971-6515 Kenneth_Ramsey@rocketmail.com https://KennethRamsey.Github.io

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full stack developer with 6 years of experience in creating and maintaining software applications. My experience lends itself to backend server side programming as well as frontend development. Passion for problem solving and logic. Extensive experience in .NET framework web based development using technologies including ASP.NET MVC, web API, C#, MS SQL Server, SSRS reports, WCF services, WiX installers, etc.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Programming Languages: C#, SQL, .NET, JavaScript, HTML & CSS

Software/Databases: ASP.NET MVC, Web API, MS SQL Server, DB2, Bootstrap, HTML 5,

CSS, JQuery, KnockoutJS, AngularJS, GIT, TFS, WPF, SSRS Reports

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

WHEELER FLEET SOLUTIONS, INC., Somerset, Pennsylvania

2017 - 2021

.NET Developer

- Maintained e-commerce websites <u>www.WheelerFleet.com</u>, <u>www.UltraSeating.com</u>, and internal Wheeler Fleet websites.
- Maintained and improved website mip.c.teamwbi.com, the inventory management website for auto mechanic shops that bought from Wheeler Fleet on consignment.
- Migrated features from the previous version of mip.c.teamwbi.com built using ASP.NET / AS400 RPG programming.
- Created windows services to periodically pull data from blackberryAPI services for participating customers.
- Created and maintained Html emails for internal and external use.
- Create SQL queries for their DB2 database.

CORE TECHS, Kernersville, NC

2015 - 2017

Software Engineer

- Improved and maintained 'TrueChecks 5.0', a C#/ASP.NET MVC 5 website and API. Deployed updates to the website using Octopus.
- Wrote custom data loaders for new clients of 'TrueCards', a C#/WPF application that helped perform fraud investigations on credit card information using MS SQL server database.
- Performed TrueCards installs and upgrades for clients (created database with proper permissions, installed and tested loader service).
- Performed remote support debugging for TrueChecks and TrueCards clients.
- Created SQL queries/stored procedures for a SQL database.

Assisted in maintaining and migrating TrueChecks 4.0, a legacy WCF service.

JOHN RAMSEY CPA, Austin, TX

2013 - 2014

Jr. Accountant

- Prepared tax returns for individuals and monthly bookkeeping for several clients.
- Updated work methods through modern and custom programs.

NANOPHOTONICS & LASER MATERIALS, Austin, TX

2010 - 2011

Laboratory Research Assistant

- Operated several class IV lasers along with a Transmission Electron Microscope.
- Gathered and analyzed spectral data within many samples and presented research findings at several science conferences.

EDUCATION

CODER FOUNDRY, Kernersville, NC 2014

ASP.NET MVC Master Class Student

- Created a personal portfolio website using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Created a fully functional MVC bug tracker web application, from scratch, implementing enhanced security and file uploading features.
- Created a fully functional financial portal web application using .NET & Angular framework.
- Created a fully functioning mobile vehicle information MVC application. Included images using Google API. Built RESTful API.

Bachelors of Science in Physics - Minor in Mathematics

The University of Texas at San Antonio, San Antonio, TX - 2011